onlinecollege.org 2018-03-20

# Privacy Policy - OnlineCollege.org

Terms of Use and Privacy Policy for Use of OnlineCollege.org (Effective January 6, 2016)

Thank you for your interest in OnlineCollege.org, and for making use of our content and services. Here, we will discuss the conditions under which you may utilize our website, as well as ways in which OnlineCollege.org gathers and uses different types of information so that we can provide user-relevant content and related products and services.

In using OnlineCollege.org, you are agreeing to the following Terms of Use and Privacy Policy. You agree and acknowledge that information collected on this website may be shared with schools, affiliated companies, and third parties for the purpose of providing you with information you have expressed interest in, such as degrees, programs, and other education-related products and services. You also acknowledge and agree that we retain the right to release any collected information as needed to businesses providing OnlineCollege.org with administrative services, such as an email delivery service. This includes personally identifiable information.

By submitting personal information to OnlineCollege.org, you are granting permission for us, our affiliated entities (including schools, third party marketing partners, and vendors) to contact you via telephone, text messages, email, and/or mail for the purpose of providing information and marketing for education-related products and services. In addition, through this action, you grant us and our affiliates, partners, and vendors the right to contact you for a period of time. This will relinquish any rights granted to you by the Do Not Call list or other applicable law because by submitting personal information on this website, you omit yourself from the Do Not Call requirements established by state and federal governments. This may exempt us from other applicable laws.

We also retain the right to release your personal information in circumstances where it is required by law, such as to abide by a subpoena or other legal procedure. This will be done when, in good faith, we believe it is necessary to preserve our rights, to explore alleged fraud, to ensure the safety of you or others, to reply to a government or legal request, and/or in the instance that OnlineCollege.org is merging, acquisitioning, or selling some or all of its assets to a third party.

OnlineCollege.org generally collects two types of data: submitted and automatic information. 

### Submitted Information

This type of information is voluntarily provided by the user, and may include:

  * Name
  * Phone number
  * Address
  * Email
  * Any other information required to match you to a product or service

This is usually submitted through a web form and is collected and stored by OnlineCollege.org. We share this information with schools and other third parties as necessary to provide you with relevant information about schools, programs, and education-related services. By submitting this information, you authorize OnlineCollege.org, along with our affiliated schools and partners, to contact you in accordance with all applicable laws. This may be done by telephone, text message, email, and/or mail, for the purpose of relaying information about education options or related topics. Specifically, if you receive any email communications from us, a school, or third party, you can unsubscribe through a link in the email. This will remove you from the mailing list of that sender.

### Automatic information

Automatic information is data collected and stored whenever visitors interact with OnlineCollege.org, and includes (but is not limited to):

  * Browser version
  * Operating system version
  * IP address

This is anonymous information, and is used to aid us in improving the website and creating a more relevant user experience. To collect this automatic data, we use “cookies” to gather the data, which is then utilized for analytics, site optimization, and for tailored advertising and marketing purposes. 

By using this website, you acknowledge that OnlineCollege.org uses cookies and consent to our use of cookies. Cookies are small pieces of data sent from a website and stored in the user’s web browser. These are used for technical purposes, such as web analytics. OnlineCollege.org’s web analytics are mainly run using Google Analytics, a tool provided by Google, Inc. These advertising cookies, which are sometimes referred to as third-party cookies because they track navigation and publish ads on behalf of third parties, do not contain personally identifiable information. They do, however, enable advertisers to make ads more relevant to the user’s interests. For more information about Google Analytics, check [Google’s privacy policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/privacyoverview.html).

Here are some examples of how we may use cookies, including uses through services and partnerships with vendors and third-party service providers:

  * Looking at demographic and other anonymous data for web optimization and other analysis
  * “Lead auditing” to ensure the accuracy, relevance, and validity of submitted information
  * Marketing and conversion tracking cookies, used for targeting and optimizing digital ad serving to improve relevance, user experience, and advertising effectiveness

You can remove cookies through your browser settings at any time, but you may need to do this on a per use basis. You can also generally opt out of receiving personalized ads from third-party advertisers and ad networks that are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) or that follow the Digital Advertising Alliance’s Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. To do so, visit the opt-out pages on the NAI website and DAA websites.

## Terms of Use and Privacy Policy Changes Notification

We could possibly revise our Terms of Use and Privacy Policy in the future if we change our practices. To remain current and informed on our policies, we recommend that you revisit this page periodically.

If you have any questions or concerns about this Terms of Use and Privacy Policy, please use our contact form.
